hey there welcome to another interesting
lesson on this Tosca automation playlist
today I'm going to show you how you can
verify XML files using the Tosca
automation modules
now for this particular example I'm
going to use this books.xml it has got a
some information related to different
books it's a catalog of books with
different
um properties like ID author title
general price and some other information
now we are going to use the Tosca
modules to basically scan this XML file
and also do some verification like if
you want to verify
um
whether some title of a particular book
ID is as per our expected result or not
okay so that's what we are going to do
and for this I'm going to use two
modules both are part of the XML engine
so let's create a test case here called
verify XML
and then I am going to search for this
modules so let's search with XML
and I'm going to use the open create XML
file
and I'm going to use
verify XML
okay so these are the two modules which
we can use uh the first module is to
open or it can also create a new XML
file so for this we need to give a
resource now research could be anything
uh for me I will just give it a name
called books XML
and then the file path okay so let's
copy the file path here
and let's come here and then paste it
here so this is the file path now while
verifying the XML file we need to
provide the same resource which we used
while opening it
so we'll mention books XML here
now we need to give the X path
okay so in an XML file if you want to
access any particular node you need to
provide the path of that node in the XML
tree okay
so for example if we are looking at this
XML file okay so if we want to Traverse
to a certain book okay book ID we need
to give the path of this particular node
okay so whatever node we are trying to
access we need to provide the path of it
so the easiest way to do this
um is either use
um
some tool to generate the expert or you
can write your own expert if you know
how to write it okay so that's what I'm
going to do
okay so to do that I will first go to
this XML file and then I will click on
right click and click on inspect okay so
that will give me a kind of an XML tree
okay with all the different nodes you
can see here
so here I can then press Ctrl F and then
you will see there is a find by a text
box okay where I can write and I can
also verify my XPath okay so for example
I want to verify the title of this
particular book which is microsoft.net
so in order to access this I need to
write a relative expert so I'll start
off by writing book
okay so that will probably give me all
the list
of nodes which start with the book tag
okay and then I'm going to say at ID
equals
I'm going to give it a value here so
it's pk110
okay so this will filter it down to that
specific book with this particular ID
okay and then I'm going to access the
title here so I'm going to write title
and that will filter it out again to
highlight the title here okay so this is
probably
the expat for if you want to access this
particular node okay
so as I want to verify the title I will
take this node
I will go back to Tosca and now I will
paste it here
now you need to take care of this
particular Expressions because there are
some special characters in this
particular expert okay and you need to
tell Tosca to escape the special
characters otherwise it will throw some
errors so you can go and right click on
this and you can say Escape value
okay
uh
that will escape the special characters
here but again we need to escape this
particular string value for ID okay so
better
we provide some quotes double quotes
here okay
so you need to put two double quotes one
is for the X path and one uh it is still
in Tosca to basically consider this as a
string okay
so this is how your expert should look
like
and now we want to verify something in
the value okay so
um
if you look at this value it's
microsoft.net and then the programming
Bible
um I don't want to write the whole text
so I can use some regular expression
here so I can write Microsoft and then I
can put a star
so that whatever text after that it can
just verify that okay
so any text which is uh starting with
Microsoft and then
um it can be anything after this okay
so this way I want to verify the value
of that particular title so I can do any
number of verifications by giving the X
part and then the value
okay
so let's go ahead and run this quickly
and you will see that it will show you
all the steps which it has performed and
on the X path it will say verification
was successful so expression was this
actual value was this right
so this is how you can verify any
particular XML file using these two
modules which are part of the XML engine
and one is the open create XML file and
the other is verify X summary
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments
if you like this video then please
subscribe to our Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video